Nice to meet you. I'm Teruo Akimoto.
很高兴认识你 我叫秋本辉夫
Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
I'm Mai Hanasaki.
我叫花琦舞
Ms. Hanasaki, what's your hobby?
花琦小姐有什么爱好呢？
My hobby?
爱好啊
I guess it's reading and travelling.
应该是阅读和旅游吧
I see.
这样啊
I love travelling too.
我也喜欢旅游
Ms. Hanasaki,
花琦小姐
don't you have any questions for him?
你没有问题要问他吗？
Me? Well…
我吗？
not really…
没有呢
That's not good. You can't get to know him like that.
那可不行 这样没办法了解他
Women have to be more proactive these days.
现在的女人要更主动
Wait. Hold on a second. It's almost as if
等一下 这是要
you're setting me up with him.
把我和他凑在一起？
-What? You didn't know? -It is?
-怎么？你不知道吗？ -真的是啊？
-What? It's not? -Wait…
-什么？不是吗？ -等等
I only came because Ms. Shizue invited me for tea… what?
我来是因为静枝女士邀请我喝茶
What? She told me
可是她告诉我
that she wants to introduce me to someone.
她想帮我介绍女朋友
Ms. Shizue…
静枝女士
Who cares about how we got here.
不用管我们为什么来这里
I've always wanted to introduce you two to each other.
我一直想介绍你们两位认识
You two look very good together, just like I imagined.
跟我想的一样 你们看起来很般配
But it's so sudden…
但是那么突然…
Y… yeah, you're making her uncomfortable.
是啊 对花琦小姐太失礼了
Mr. Akimoto
秋本先生
is a businessman at Keihin Bank
是京滨银行的业务员
and he's helped me out a lot.
他帮了我好多忙
-Oh, you're a banker? -Yes.
-你是银行从业者啊？ -是
I told you about Ms. Hanasaki before, right?
我跟你提过花琦小姐 对吧？
When I was living in Akasaka,
我住在赤坂的时候
she was the cutest and most competent banker in Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
她曾是东京第一银行 最可爱、最优秀的职员
Oh, please don't say that… Was that past tense?
请别那么说 曾是… 过去式了吗？
-Oh… -I contacted her recently.
我最近联系她
She said that she's not married yet so I knew I had to help her.
她说她还没结婚 我就知道我得帮她
Both of you are bankers,
你们两位都在银行工作
so you must get along.
一定处得来
No, unlike Tokyo Daiichi Bank, our bank is
可是我们不像东京第一银行
just a small local one.
我们只是小型地区银行
But I like local banks that work closely with the region,
我喜欢与地方密切合作的地区银行
because they get things done very quickly.
因为他们办事效率高
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -是的
That makes me happy.
真高兴听你这么说
Mr. Akimoto is so nice and kind.
秋本先生人很好 很亲切
-Welcome. -Hello.
-欢迎 -你好
Every time he would come, he would change my lightbulbs
他每次来都帮我换灯泡
and carry heavy items for me.
帮我搬重的东西
He's like a real grandson to me.
他就像我的孙子一样
I see.
原来如此
But apparently, he doesn't have good results as a banker.
不过 显然他当职员的业绩不好
-That's why I'm worried. -Oh.
所以我才担心
No need to mention that.
那个就不要提了
Ms. Hanasaki was a lovely teller.
花琦小姐是讨人喜欢的柜员
I secretly took two number tickets
我都偷偷拿两张号码牌
because I wanted to go to Ms. Hanasaki's window.
因为我想去花琦小姐的窗口
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的吗？ -真的
-Ms. Sekiguchi. -Yes.
-静枝女士 -是
Thank you for waiting.
谢谢耐心等候
She was still a rookie,
她那时还是新员工
but she was a fast worker, and very detailed.
但是她动作快又仔细
And above all, she had a very nice smile.
最重要的是她笑容甜美
I know for sure
我很肯定
that Ms. Hanasaki will make a great wife.
花琦小姐一定会是个好太太
Oh stop it, Ms. Shizue.
静枝女士 别说了
Oh man, I had to pay for another wedding gift.
我又得包喜酒红包
It's already been… three times this year.
这已经是今年第三次了
I need a break.
真希望能体谅我一下
But the bride was pretty cute.
不过新娘子长得真可爱
What are you saying?
你说什么呢？
You're partnered with a young lady, right?
你的工作搭档不是一个年轻淑女吗？
-I'm so jealous. -Hold on. I told you before.
-真羡慕 -等等 我跟你说过了
She is not a lady.
她不是淑女
You should see her face when she gets mad.
她生气时的表情超吓人的
-Really? -Yeah, she won't be doing it.
-真的吗？ -是啊 想必她
Getting married anytime soon.
是嫁不出去的
Hey, you want to get some coffee?
对了 你要喝咖啡吗？
Apparently, this café has an amazing chocolate cake.
这家咖啡厅的巧克力蛋糕很棒
Ch… chocolate… oh…
巧克力
No, I can't. My wife will be mad, so I'll go home.
不行 我老婆会生气 我要回家了
-See you later. -Bye.
-再见了 -再见
Hanasaki…
花琦
I'm 26 years old.
我26岁
Oh? Is she being set up with someone?
她是在相亲吗？
How old are you, Mr. Akimoto?
秋本先生 你几岁呢？
-I'm two years older than you. -This way.
-我大你两岁 -这边
-Coffee and chocolate cake, please. -That's perfect.
-咖啡和巧克力蛋糕 谢谢 -那最合适了
-Okay. -Two years older is perfect.
-是吗？ -大两岁最合适
I thought we were about the same age.
我以为我们同龄
I can't hear anything.
听不到
Sir…
先生
is something the matter?
有什么问题吗？
Oh, I was looking for some napkins.
我在找餐巾纸
-Mr. Soma. -Oh!
-相马先生 -哦
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
I was so surprised,
我很讶异
to see you being set up with someone.
看到你在相亲
Like I said, I was not being set up.
我说了 我不是去相亲
I was invited by Ms. Shizue
静枝女士邀请我
to have tea together.
去和她喝茶
By the way, why do you have to come here on your day off?
对了 你休假干嘛还来这里？
She's so brave to set you up with someone.
她帮你安排相亲还真是勇敢
Are you listening to me?
你有在听我说话吗？
Is she your relative?
她是你的亲戚吗？
Ms. Shizue
静枝女士
was a customer when I worked in Akasaka.
是我在赤坂工作时的客户
What?
什么？
I met her when I first
我是刚进银行时认识她的
started the job and we've been friends since.
之后就成了朋友
So…
那么
who was the other guy?
那个男的是谁？
His name is Akimoto
他姓秋本
and he works in Public Relations at Keihin Bank.
他在京滨银行涉外课做事
Like I said, we were not set up.
我说了 我们不是去相亲
Ms. Shizue really likes Mr. Akimoto
静枝女士很喜欢秋本先生
so she tried to set me up with him. That's all.
所以她想撮合我跟他 如此而已
Hey Mai, you were set up?
舞 你去相亲？
You met him? You didn't tell me that.
你们见面了？你怎么没告诉爸爸？
No, I didn't.
我没有
Mr. Soma, please keep your mouth shut.
相马先生 拜托你别多嘴
I'm not saying that you shouldn't see anyone.
我不是说你不应该去认识人
But you just have to tell me these things.
可是这种事情你要告诉我
-It seems like he's a banker. -What? Really?
-他好像也在银行工作 -真的吗？
Then you have my support.
那么我支持你
A banker's wife is your dream.
嫁给银行从业者是你的梦想
That was never my dream!
我从来没有那种梦想
-Good luck! -Mai.
-加油 -舞
-Good luck! -Good luck, Mai!
-加油 舞
MAY 30TH FRIDAY
（5月30日 星期五）
Today's inspection is done!
今天的分行稽核完成了
It was another busy week.
又是忙碌的一周
-Yeah. -I feel like it.
-是啊 -我觉得
Like I've gotten used to this job.
我已经习惯这个工作了
Yeah. You did well.
对 你做得很好
You didn't get mad all week either.
也没有一整个星期都在生气
All right.
很好
I'll be reading Kaido wo Yuku this weekend.
这个周末我要读《走在路上》
What? You have no plans this weekend?
怎么？你周末没有计划吗？
Not really.
没有
What happened to that guy you were set up with?
那个相亲男没动静吗？
I haven't contacted him.
我没联系他
What are you doing?
你在干嘛啊？
You're young and hip, so go have some fun.
你年轻又时髦 去好好玩一玩
Young and hip?
年轻又时髦？
This is why I can't be with old men.
所以我才没办法和老头子相处
Yes, I'm old. So what?
我就是老头子 怎样？
We're in trouble!
出事了！
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
What?
奇怪？
They're not here.
他们不在
Soon you'll be an old lady.
你很快就会变成老女人
You'll be even older then.
那么你会变得更老
-You little… -What's the matter, Mr. Shibasaki?
-你这个… -芝崎次长 出了什么事？
We're in trouble!
出大事了
The guy you were set up with worked at Keihin Bank, right?
和你相亲那个男的 在京滨银行上班 对吧？
Yes… wait, how do you know that… Mr. Soma, you told him?
对 你怎么知道？ 相马先生 你告诉他的？
-Why would I tell him? -Then how does he know?
-我为什么要告诉他？ -那他是怎么知道的？
Who cares about that?
那件事不重要啦！
It collapsed.
它倒闭了
-A lapse? -No, collapsed. Here!
-倒闭？ -对 倒闭 看这个
What?
什么？
Keihin Bank collapsed!
京滨银行倒闭了！
Collapsed?
-倒闭？
KEIHIN BANK COLLAPSES AFFECTING OVER 3 MILLION PEOPLE
（京滨银行倒闭 超过三百万人受影响）
Keihin Bank has collapsed.
京滨银行已经倒闭
They officially filed for bankruptcy with the Financial Services Agency.
他们正式向金融厅申请破产
According to the conference held by the Minister of Finance,
根据金融担当大臣举行的会议
Keihin Bank's debt is
京滨银行的负债
estimated to be over 150 billion yen.
估计超过一千五百亿日元
Keihin Bank is a local bank with branches around Tokyo and Kanagawa,
京滨银行是地方银行 分行散布在东京与神奈川
and this collapse is predicted to affect
据估计 这次倒闭将影响
over three million people.
超过三百万人
Keihin Bank's management
京滨银行的经营管理
was technically running on debt.
严格来说是债务累累
I hear their subsidiary companies were all in the red too.
听说他们的子公司也都是赤字
That doesn't sound good.
听起来不妙啊
Well, collapse
像我们这样的大型银行
is unheard of for a large bank like ours--
不曾听过有倒闭这种事
You're naïve.
你太天真
A small leak will sink a great ship.
小漏能沉大船
Sink… a ship?
沉船？
A little negligence
微小疏忽
will lead to great collapse.
将导致严重倒闭
Yes!
是
-Kodama… -Yes, sir.
-儿玉 -是
Always be on alert.
随时保持警觉
You, yourself,
对你我来说
never know when and where
永远不知道危险
danger may strike you.
会在何时和何处袭来
Yes, sir.
是
Collapsed, huh?
倒闭啊…
It means they are bankrupt, right?
表示他们无力偿还债务 对吧？
Yeah,
没错
but it's not the same as a regular company's bankruptcy.
不过这和一般公司的倒闭不同
Yeah, because banks handle customers' money.
对 因为银行负责处理客户的钱
Is our bank safe?
我们银行安全吗？
I'm sure it is,
我相信是没问题
but it could happen to anyone.
但是这种事可能发生在任何银行
Is your future boyfriend all right?
你未来的男朋友还好吗？
Yeah, I was just thinking about that…
我也正想到那个…
He's not my future boyfriend.
我都说了 他不是我未来的男朋友
Hello. Ms. Shizue?
喂 静枝女士吗？
Ms. Hanasaki, I'm sorry it's so sudden
花琦小姐 抱歉突然打给你
but can we meet and talk?
我们可以见面谈吗？
Are you okay?
怎么了吗？
I need your advice on something.
我需要听你的建议
Advice?
建议？
KEIHIN BANK COLLAPSES AFFECTING OVER 3 MILLION PEOPLE
（京滨银行倒闭 超过三百万人受影响）
I understand. I'll visit your house tomorrow, Ms. Shizue.
我知道了 那么我明天去拜访您
Okay.
好
KUGAHARA
（久原中高层住宅）
SHIZUE SEKIGUCHI
（关口静枝）
Welcome.
欢迎
-Come in. -Ms. Shizue, this is for you.
-请进 -静枝女士 这是送你的
It's nerikiri from Shinanoya in Akasaka.
这是赤坂信浓屋的和果子
-You remembered that I like this? -Yes.
-你记得我爱吃这个啊？ -是
My late husband loved this too.
我过世的先生也爱吃
I gave him this to put him in a good mood.
我都用这个哄他开心
I see.
这样啊
Ms. Shizue,
静枝女士
did you want my advice regarding this?
你要我给你建议是关于这个吗？
Yes. I was so shocked because it was so sudden.
是啊 我吓到了 太突然了
How much was your deposit?
你的存款有多少呢？
My checking account has
我的活期存款
about 500,000 yen.
有大约五十万日元
-Fixed deposit account has 20 million yen. -Twenty million yen?
-定期存款有两千万日元 -两千万？
Excuse me.
我看一下
SHIZUE SEKIGUCHI
（关口静枝）
I cancelled the fixed deposit account
其实我取消了
I had made at your bank
在你们银行开的定期帐户
and changed it to Keihin Bank.
改存到京滨银行
-I see. -I'm sorry.
-这样啊 -真抱歉
Especially as you helped me open that account.
难得你帮我开了那个定期帐户
Please don't worry about that.
请不用担心那个
You remember Mr. Akimoto, right?
你记得秋本先生吧？
He wasn't meeting his quota, so I helped him out.
因为他没有达到业绩 所以我就帮他
That's very you, Ms. Shizue.
这真的是静枝女士会做的事
Tell me, what will happen to my money
我问你 银行倒了
when the bank collapses?
我的钱怎么办？
There is something called the deposit guarantee system.
有个叫做存款保证的系统
Basically, ten million yen that you have in the bank,
简单说 放在银行中的一千万日元
and its interest is guaranteed.
以及利息会受到保障
Nothing more than that?
就只有这样子吗？
I can't say much on that matter.
这个问题我没办法说太多
I see.
这样啊
Mr. Akimoto hasn't explained anything?
秋本先生都没解释吗？
Yeah, it seems like he's really busy.
对 他好像很忙
How irresponsible… He's the person in charge of your account.
真不负责任 他是负责你帐户的人
It can't be helped. I'm not his only customer.
那也没办法 我不是他唯一的客户
I'm sure there are lots of people who have larger amounts of deposits.
我相信有大额存款的人很多
The amount of money you have shouldn't matter.
重要的不是钱的多少
What?
什么？
MAY 26, 2014
（2014年5月26日）
This was just two weeks ago!
这才半个月前办的
Yeah. I'm so unlucky.
是啊 我真倒霉
Oh.
对了
-Hold on a second. -Sure…
-稍等一下 -好
FIXED DEPOSIT ACCOUNT
（定期帐户）
COLLAPSED
（倒闭）
Ms. Shizue, I'm so sorry I'm late.
静枝女士 抱歉我来晚了
I'm so glad to see you. Come inside.
来了就好 进来吧
Thank you. Is someone here?
谢谢 屋里有客人吗？
Nice to see you again.
很高兴又见面了
Ms. Hanasaki. I didn't expect you here.
花琦小姐 我没想到你会在这里
Hello.
你好
I'm so sorry.
静枝女士 非常对不起
I didn't know that this would happen.
我不知道会发生这种事
I'm so sorry that
我没有早一点注意到
I didn't notice any sooner.
真的很抱歉
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错
I want to give you all the money you deposited,
我想把你的存款都还给你
but there's not much I can do…
但是我能做的不多
I… don't know how I can ever make it up to you…
我不知道该怎么做才能补偿你
You handed over your precious money…
你把你宝贵的钱交给我
It can't be helped. Please don't worry about it.
那是没办法的事 请不要担心了
You're losing your job too.
你也失去了工作
So I can't blame you.
我不能责备你
I'm so sorry.
真对不起
The depositors ended up having to pay the price
存款人最后要为了
for the bank's disorderly management.
银行的管理不当付出代价
Keihin Bank's debt seems to exceed the amount that has been officially announced.
京滨银行的债务 似乎超出正式宣布的金额
Then that would mean that
那就表示
they can only guarantee up to ten million yen per account?
他们只能保证 每个帐户最高一千万元吗？
Yes, that's right. I wonder why the bank
没有错 我很讶异
couldn't do something before it collapsed.
银行无法在倒闭前做点什么吗？
What will happen to accounts with over ten million yen?
存款超过一千万的帐户会怎么样呢？
Something really bothers me.
有件事让我很困扰
What?
什么事？
Ms. Shizue showed me her passbook.
静枝女士让我看她的存折
She cancelled her account with us
她取消了在我们银行的帐户
and created an account with Keihin Bank on May 14th.
5月14日在京滨银行开了一个帐户
That's two weeks before the collapse.
那是在他们倒闭前半个月
So?
所以呢？
Isn't the timing very suspicious?
那个时间点不是很可疑吗？
Of course, Mr. Akimoto said that
当然 秋本先生说
he never thought the bank would collapse.
他没想到银行会倒闭
But why would he suggest to her to change her account at a time like this?
但是他为什么要在这种时候 建议她换帐户呢？
He was just doing his job, right?
他只是在做他的工作吧？
A regular employee has no way of knowing a collapse in advance.
一般职员不可能事先知道银行要倒闭
I know, but…
是没错 可是…
Important business is done by the top management in secrecy.
重要决策都是管理高层秘密决定的
That's how a bank works.
这就是银行
That Akimoto
那个秋本
is a victim too.
他也是受害者
But the number one victims
但是最主要的受害人
are people like Ms. Shizue who had entrusted their money to them.
是像静枝女士这种把钱托付银行的人
Yeah.
没错
Either way, it doesn't concern our bank.
不管怎样 这都和我们银行无关
There's nothing you can do about it.
你完全无能为力
I know.
我知道
But
可是
that money was like a good luck charm
那笔钱对静枝女士来说
for Ms. Shizue.
就像幸运符
-Good luck charm? -Yes.
-幸运符？ -对
TATSUHIRO SEKIGUCHI
（关口辰裕）
All of this is for the fixed deposit account?
这些全部要存定期吗？
Yes.
是
It's money that my husband left me when he passed away last month.
这是我上个月过世的先生留给我的
-He left it for me. -Are you sure you want a fixed account?
-他把钱留给我 -你确定吗？
It will be difficult to withdraw from…
定期存款的话 要取钱会很困难
I don't plan on using this money.
我不打算使用这笔钱
Because it's like my good luck charm.
因为它是我的幸运符
I see. A good luck charm, huh?
我懂了 幸运符
I feel sick.
我觉得不舒服
-Good morning. -Mr. Shibasaki, did you drink too much?
-早安 -芝崎次长 又喝过头了吗？
A junior of mine worked at Keihin Bank.
我一个学弟在京滨银行
He dragged me to three places,
他拉我去了三个地方
and I had to listen to him complain.
我不得不听他诉苦
-My sympathies. -He said that a lot of employees left.
-真同情你 -他说京滨银行倒闭前
They were leaving Keihin Bank before the collapse,
很多职员都离职了
but he didn't leave early enough.
但是他离开得不够早
What?
什么？
Then the employees knew about the collapse?
那么员工都知道银行要倒闭？
Yeah. It seems like they were all talking about
对 似乎所有人上班时都在谈论
the imminent collapse.
银行即将倒闭
Their organization was on the verge of disintegrating.
他们的组织濒临瓦解
Your junior works at headquarters or something, right?
你的学弟是在总部工作吧？
No, he works at the branch.
不是 他在分行的营业课
Oh, my head is pounding.
我的头好痛
Please stamp your seal on this.
请在这上面盖章
Oh boy.
天啊
Things aren't matching up.
事情说不通了
Yes.
对
Employees knew beforehand about the collapse, right?
员工已经知道银行要倒闭了 对吧？
Akimoto was lying.
秋本在说谎
Yeah. It would be horrible if he made
对 要是他让静枝女士开户时
Ms. Shizue open up a new account while knowing about this.
就知道会发生倒闭
-And what would happen. -Hold on.
-那就太可怕了 -等等
-Why did he do that in the first place? -What?
-他当初为什么要那么做呢？ -什么？
If he knew that his bank was about to collapse,
如果他知道他们银行即将倒闭
there's no merit in raising your quota.
那么提高业绩没有好处啊
You're right.
你说的对
Did he have a grudge against Ms. Shizue?
他对静枝女士心存怨恨吗？
We might need to investigate him.
我们可能需要调查他
Yes.
对
Oh, Ms. Hanasaki.
是花琦小姐啊
You should've told me if you already had someone like this.
你已经认识这么棒的人 就应该先告诉我
-W… what? -Huh?
-什么？
I was wondering why you weren't showing interest in Mr. Akimoto.
我就觉得奇怪 你怎么对秋本没兴趣
-Hello. -Ah, yes…
-你好 -是
-He's just my boss. -Don't be so rude.
-他只是我的上司 -还有别种说法吧？
I'm Soma. I'm just her boss.
我是相马 我只是她的上司
Oh, the one at the hotel!
在饭店的那位
-Oh… ah… -I saw you there, right?
-那个… -我在那里有看到你吧？
More importantly,
更重要的是
I came today to ask you about Mr. Akimoto.
我今天是来问你秋本先生的事
-Mr. Akimoto? -Yes.
-秋本先生？ -对
How did you meet him?
你是怎么认识他的？
How?
怎么认识吗？
Early this year,
今年初
he came by my house for a sales visit.
他来我家做业务拜访
Hello.
是
Hello. My name is Akimoto from the Kugahara Branch at Keihin Bank.
你好 我叫秋本 我是京滨银行久原分行来的
As I talked with him, I realized that he was a diligent kid,
和他谈话时 我发现他是个勤快的孩子
so I opened up a checking account at Keihin Bank.
于是我在京滨银行开了一个活期帐户
After that, he offered to come to my house so that I wouldn't have to
在那之后 他主动说要来我家
go to the bank and wait in line for a teller,
这样我就不必去银行排队等柜员
and even gave me financial advice.
他甚至还给我财务建议
He was a special presence for an old lady
对于我这个独居的老太太来说
living by herself.
他是非常特别的存在
What did he say when he asked you to change your account?
他请你更换定期帐户时
To a fixed deposit one?
-说了什么吗？ -嗯
Well,
说了什么…
he was really down because his boss got mad at him for not meeting
他心情很低落 因为他没有达到业绩
his quota,
他的上司很生气
so he begged me for help.
所以他求我帮忙
FIXED DEPOSIT ACCOUNT
（定期帐户）
Ms. Shizue, can you terminate this account
静枝女士 你可以终止这个帐户
and open a new account with us?
然后在我们银行新开一个吗？
We have a higher interest rate,
我们给的利息比较高
so it's more profitable for you in the long run.
长时间下来对你有利
I see.
这样啊
I promise I won't allow you to suffer a loss,
我保证不会让你蒙受损失
so I'm begging you.
我求你了
Stop that. Get up.
别那样 快起来
I'll move my account.
我改存你们银行
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -真的
I'm so glad! Thank you so much!
我太高兴了 太感谢你了
Thank you.
谢谢
THE INTEREST RATE WILL BE DEDUCTED
（帐户在约满前终止）
SINCE THE ACCOUNT WAS TERMINATED BEFORE THE FIXED TERM WAS COMPLETED
（利率将会扣除）
He's like a grandson to me,
他就像是我的孙子
so I felt really bad when he got on his knees
所以他下跪求我时
and begged me like that.
我很难过
Did you notice
你有注意到
anything strange about Mr. Akimoto?
秋本先生有任何奇怪的地方吗？
-Anything strange? -Yes.
-奇怪的地方？ -对
For example, did he push any other financial options on you,
例如他有推销其他金融产品
or something else like…
或者诸如此类的
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
you shouldn't doubt people like that.
你不应该那样怀疑别人
But…
可是
that money had important meaning to you…
那笔钱对你有重要意义
It's okay,
没关系
because I was able to help Mr. Akimoto with that.
因为我可以用它来帮助秋本先生
Of course, it's frustrating.
当然 这种事让人沮丧
But people are more important than money.
但是人比金钱更重要
Yes.
是
-Oh. -What?
-对了 -怎么了？
I had something to give her. Let me go back.
我有东西要给她 我回去一下
Okay.
好
I'm so sorry.
对不起
You worked so hard to leave me with this money…
你那么辛苦工作 留那笔钱给我
What do you think, Mr. Soma?
你怎么想 相马先生？
I don't have a good feeling about this.
感觉不太对劲
I agree.
我同意
If Akimoto is really
如果秋本真的
the nice guy that Ms. Shizue says he is,
是像静枝女士说的那么好的人
he would have waited until the fixed term came to an end.
他会等那笔定期到期
Otherwise, she loses out.
不然就损失大了
But he didn't explain that to Ms. Shizue either.
而且他也没有对静枝女士解释
Yeah.
嗯
He's definitely hiding something.
他肯定有所隐瞒
Hiding what?
隐瞒什么？
I don't know what, but…
我不知道 不过…
Is someone here?
屋里有客人吗？
Nice to see you again.
很高兴又见面了
It seemed like he had something to hide.
他似乎在隐瞒什么
I'm going to go see Mr. Akimoto.
我要去找秋本先生
If he really tricked Ms. Shizue…
如果他真的欺骗静枝女士
I will never forgive him.
我对不会原谅他
Here you go.
给你
Mr. Soma, who is that?
相马先生 那是谁？
Oh… I wonder…
我想…
-Is he Mai's new boyfriend? -No.
-难道是舞的新男朋友？ -不是
-I don't think so. -Are they okay by themselves?
-我认为不是 -他们两个在一起没问题吗？
-Let me go check. -Oh, wait.
-我去看看 -等等
Can I have some asparagus, please?
可以给我芦笋吗？
What?
什么？
-Asparagus? -Yes, asparagus.
-芦笋？ -对 芦笋
-Okay… -Thank you.
-好 -谢谢
-Here you go.
-来 请用
I didn't think I'd get a call from you.
我没想到会接到你的电话
I'll pour.
我来倒
Thank you.
谢谢
I probably shouldn't be doing this
我就要失去工作
when I'm about to lose my job.
大概不应该来这里
Let's raise our glasses for now.
我们来举杯吧
Cheers.
干杯
Well,
那个
I always knew that I wasn't cut out to be a banker.
我一直知道我不是当银行从业者的料
I'm horrible at calculating too.
我对算钱也很不在行
How does it feel to see your
看到工作的地方倒闭
workplace collapse?
是什么感觉呢？
I haven't come to terms with it.
我还无法接受
I was being told to acquire accounts
直到昨天 我还被要求
and investment funds until yesterday…
增加开户量和投资基金
but now they're telling me to tie up loose ends.
现在却要我完成最后琐碎的工作
As the person in charge,
身为负责的人
I can't face my customers anymore.
我再也没脸见我的客户
If I'd known about the collapse,
要是我早知道公司要倒闭
I could have spared Ms. Shizue from experiencing all this.
一定不让静枝女士经历这一切
I can't beat around the bush,
我不擅长拐弯抹角
so I'll be frank.
我就直说了
What?
什么？
Mr. Akimoto, didn't you already know for some time that Keihin Bank
秋本先生 你不是已经知道京滨银行
was going to collapse?
就要倒闭了吗？
-What are you saying? -Please answer me.
-你在说什么？ -请你回答我
There's no way I would've known.
我不可能事先知道
I heard that it was a hot topic among the employees since earlier this year.
我听说这件事在年初 就是职员之间的热门话题
I didn't know.
我不知道
You changed Ms. Shizue's fixed deposit account
你将静枝女士的定期帐户
from our bank to yours
从我们银行转去你们银行
just two weeks ago, right?
是在半个月前吧？
If you knew that Keihin Bank was going to collapse,
如果你知道京滨银行即将倒闭
why would you make her move her account by ending her contract early?
为什么要让她的帐户提早解约呢？
I just don't understand your actions.
我实在不明白你的做法
Ms. Shizue was very sad.
静枝女士非常伤心
Is there a reason behind all this?
背后有什么理由吗？
That's enough!
够了！
Oh, please wait.
请等一下
You called me here to ask me that?
你打电话找我来是要问这个？
I'm telling you that I didn't know anything.
我说了 我什么都不知道
I wanted to raise my sales performance, that's all.
我只是想提高业绩 仅此而已
You're just
你生我的气
angry at me because she cancelled
只是因为她取消了
the fixed deposit account you created.
你开的那个定期帐户
That's not true.
才不是那样
You don't even have proof,
你连证据都没有
but you're trying to make me look like a criminal.
就想让我看起来像罪犯
Ms. Mai Hanasaki of Tokyo Daiichi Bank,
东京第一银行的花琦舞小姐
I can sue you for defamation.
我可以告你诽谤
Ms. Shizue isn't sad at all.
静枝女士才不难过
She was happy
她很开心
because I was like a real grandson to her.
因为我对她来说就像真正的孙子
Are you leaving now?
你要离开了吗？
Did my daughter do something to upset you?
我女儿做了什么让你生气的事吗？
Thank you.
谢谢光临
He gets me so mad!
真让人火大！
What happened, Mai? He got mad and left.
舞 怎么了？他气得走掉了
Moreover, who is that?
而且他是谁？
Well… it's complicated.
一言难尽
I see.
这样啊
The way he got mad seemed like you hit a nerve.
他气成那样 看来你戳到他痛处了
He finally showed his true colors.
他终于露出真面目了
Although we still didn't get any answers.
虽然我们还没得到任何答案
But just now,
不过就在刚才
I saw something very interesting inside his wallet.
我看见他皮夹里 有个很有意思的东西
-What? -A Tokyo Daiichi Bank ATM card.
-什么东西？ -东京第一银行的提款卡
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
He has an account with our bank.
他在我们银行有帐户
We might find something if we check his account.
我们查他的帐户或许会有发现
Yes.
是
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
TERUO AKIMOTO
（顾客姓名：秋本辉夫）
-There are 11 people with the same name. -Yes.
-叫这个名字的有11个人 -对
Who lives within Tokyo?
谁住在东京？
Wakayama, Okayama,
和歌山、冈山
Hiroshima, Fukuoka.
广岛、福冈
These five people here.
这五个
Do you know how old Mr. Akimoto is?
你知道秋本先生几岁吗？
He said he's two years older than me.
他说他大我两岁
So his birth year is either 1985 or 1986.
所以是1985年 或者1986年出生的
Which means…
意思就是
It's either one of these two accounts.
这两个其中之一
It's this one.
是这个
How do you know?
你怎么知道的？
Look.
你看
He didn't specify his workplace.
他没有注明工作地点
Hello, this is Keihin Bank Kugahara Branch.
您好 这里是京滨银行久原分行
I'm sorry, I got the wrong number.
抱歉 我打错电话了
Bingo.
对了
The account number is…
帐号是…
TERUO AKIMOTO
（姓名：秋本辉夫）
A balance of 4,210 yen?
余额是4210日元？
He's transferring money every month to a real estate company.
他每个月都转帐到一个房地产公司
It seems like an account to pay for rent.
看起来这是付房租的帐户
This doesn't give us any information.
这样就无从知道了
Hold on a second.
等一下
-What's this transfer? -Tokyo First Stock, Akimoto Teruo.
-这笔汇款是什么？ -东京第一证券 秋本辉夫
He's a banker, but he has stocks?
他是银行从业者 可是他有股票？
-This is prohibited at our bank. -Yeah, this is suspicious.
-这在我们银行是禁止的 -对 这很可疑
Wasn't he saying that he's not good at calculating?
他不是说他不擅长算钱吗？
Yes.
对
Can we investigate what these transactions are for?
我们可以调查这些交易的目的吗？
I guess that would be hard with a brokerage firm.
我猜要查证券商会很困难
-No… there is a way. -What?
-不 有办法 -什么？
My colleague was dispatched to this place.
我同期的同事刚调去那里
Tokyo First Stock is our affiliate.
东京第一证券是我们的子公司
Right.
对
TOKYO FIRST STOCK KAWASAKI BRANCH
（东京第一证券 川崎分行）
Branch Manager Azuma please.
我们找东经理
Yes.
好的
Since it's an affiliate company, it has the same atmosphere.
果然是我们的子公司 连气氛都一样
Listen up. Just stay still and be quiet.
听好 你就安静坐好
Yes.
是
Hey, Soma!
相马
Sorry for coming without notice.
抱歉 没先通知就过来了
-This is Azuma. He's the branch manager. -Hello.
-这位是东 这里的分行经理 -你好
-I'm Mai Hanasaki. -Oh, you're Ms. Hanasaki!
-我是花琦 -你就是花琦小姐啊！
-I heard about you. -What?
-久仰大名 -什么？
She's nothing like how you described.
她和你描述的完全不一样
Well…
那个…
He said that you were not ladylike,
他说你不像个淑女
and that you're scary when you're mad.
而且你生气起来很吓人
Oh, is that so?
是那样吗？
-What are you doing? -Sit down.
-你干嘛？ -请坐
I'll get you back for this.
我会向你讨回来的
What brings you here today?
你们今天为了什么事情过来？
Well, it's a bit troublesome, but…
有点麻烦 不过…
What?
什么事？
This man named Teruo Akimoto has an account with
这个叫做秋本辉夫的人
Tokyo First Stock.
有东京第一证券的户头
And?
那怎么样？
We want the investment information.
我们想要他的投资资料
Did this guy do something?
这个人做了什么事吗？
We can't give you the details,
没办法告诉你细节
but he might be doing illegal things.
不过他可能在做违法的事
That's it? That's impossible and you know it.
就这样？你知道那是不可能的
-I know that, but I want you to try. -Please.
-我知道 可是我希望你试试看 -拜托
I'm sure you know, but although we're an affiliate,
我相信你知道 我们虽然是子公司
we're separate from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
但是我们和东京第一银行是分开的
We can't leak customer information to an outside source.
我们不能泄漏客户资料给外部的人
Azuma.
东
He's a banker at Keihin Bank.
他是京滨银行的职员
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -真的
This company isn't allowed to trade stocks with a banker, right?
这家证券公司不允许 与银行从业者交易股票 对吧？
Damn it.
可恶
That doesn't mean I can simply look up…
那不表示我就能那么简单查询
TERUO AKIMOTO
（顾客姓名：秋本辉夫）
He's using our branch?
他使用我们分行？
He mostly has tech-related stocks.
他持有的大部分是科技类股
It's not rare for people to make money these days
最近玩当日平盘的人
with day trade
不算少
but he's pretty clever with it.
不过他很擅长玩当日平盘
We can't look at it.
我们不能看
How is he good?
他怎么擅长？
He makes moderate profit without getting too greedy.
他赚取适当利润 不会太贪心
He doesn't lose much either.
他也没有损失太多
These detailed investments are not possible unless he's constantly checking.
除非他经常查看 否则不可能做这么精密的投资
He has the knowledge and the skills.
他具备知识和技术
-How much is his operation fund? -Brace yourselves.
-他有多少操作资金？ -你做好心理准备
His stock value is
他的股票价值是
95 million yen.
九千五百万日元
-Nine… -What?
-九… -什么？
TAKAGI
（高木来电）
Mr. Takagi?
高木先生吗？
I'm so sorry, I was about to call you just now.
对不起 我正想要打电话给你
Yes.
是
I'm so sorry that I can't do anything to help you.
真抱歉 我帮不上忙
Ninety-five million yen.
九千五百万日元
Unless he's from a wealthy family,
除非他家里非常富裕
most people in their twenties aren't that rich.
否则大部分二十几岁的人没那么多钱
Where did he get all that money?
他从哪里弄到那些钱？
In the beginning, he was operating using a small fund
他一开始是用少量资金
but he's been using tens of millions since early this year.
不过从今年初开始使用几千万日元
15 million on January 16th. 13 million on February 3rd.
1月16日使用一千五百万 2月3日使用一千三百万
20 million on May 14th.
5月14日使用两千万
What? Wait.
等一下
-What did you just say? -Hanasaki!
-你刚刚说什么？ -花琦
Twenty million on May 14th.
5月14日是两千万
He made ten deposits of two million yen each.
他存入十笔 每笔两百万
Total is 20 million.
总共两千万
May 14th is the day that Ms. Shizue moved 20 million yen
5月14日静枝女士存入两千万
to a fixed deposit account at Keihin Bank.
到京滨银行的定期帐户
If he deposited two million each, he must have used an ATM with a deposit limit.
如果每笔存两百万 一定是利用提款机的存款上限
Can you track down the ATM?
你可以追踪到哪个提款机吗？
Yeah.
可以
KUGAHARA 8-CHOME
（久原八丁目 便利商店内的提款机）
It's an ATM inside a convenience store in Kugahara.
是在久原一间便利商店内的提款机
It's right by Ms. Shizue's house.
就在静枝女士家旁边
So after Akimoto received 20 million yen from Ms. Shizue
所以秋本收到静枝女士
to open a fixed deposit account at Keihin Bank,
要在京滨银行定期的两千万
he immediately deposited that into his account at Tokyo First.
就立刻存入他在东京第一证券的户头
Embezzlement.
侵占…
But Mr. Soma,
可是相马先生
Ms. Shizue has a passbook for her account
静枝女是有她帐户的存折
and there was record of a 20-million-yen deposit.
而且上面记录了两千万日元
Okay, let's go check it out.
好 我们去查清楚
Yes.
是
Thanks, Azuma.
东 谢谢你
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
SHIZUE SEKIGUCHI
（关口静枝）
Hello.
来了
What are you two doing here?
你们两位怎么来了？
Ms. Shizue, may I see your passbook once again?
静枝女士 我可以再看一次你的存折吗？
Yeah, of course.
当然可以
I had it prepared because Mr. Akimoto
我把它准备好了 因为秋本先生说
said that he'll be by tomorrow for the passbook.
他明天会过来拿存折
-What? -I just got a call.
-什么？ -我刚刚接到电话
They're able to withdraw some money now.
现在可以提钱了
So he's going to stop by to return my ten million yen
所以他要过来还我一千万元
and pick up my passbook.
还有拿我的存折
I'm just relieved that I can at least get ten million yen back.
我松了一口气 至少能拿回一千万
Please let me see this.
请让我看一下
-Go ahead. -Thank you.
-你看吧 -谢谢
KEIHIN FIXED DEPOSIT ACCOUNT
（京滨特别定期帐户）
Yeah, the money was deposited.
果然钱有存进去
CHECKING ACCOUNT
（活期存款）
Excuse me.
我看一下
What?
什么？
-Ah! -What is it?
怎么了？
Please look at this.
你看这个
Oh.
这…
We finally solved it.
终于解开了
KEIHIN BANK KUGAHARA BRANCH
（京滨银行 久原分行）
TOKYO FIRST STOCK
（东京第一证券来电）
-Hello? -Mr. Akimoto?
-喂？ -是秋本先生吗？
Thank you for your time.
耽误你一点时间
I'm Branch Manager Azuma from the Kawasaki Branch
我是东京第一证券
of Tokyo First Stock.
川崎分行的东经理
The branch manager?
经理？
We have a new brand with high potential that we can only
是 有一支很有潜力的新股票
introduce to high profile customers.
只介绍给高资产客户
We are calling because we wanted
我们打电话来是想要
to extend the offer to you.
向您提供报价
I see.
我知道了
I'll head over there now.
我现在就过去
I understand. I'll be expecting you.
好的 我等您过来
Thank you.
谢谢
KEIHIN BANK
（京滨银行）
May I see the branch manager?
你好 我想找分行经理
I understand.
好的
Please wait here.
请在这里等候
What? Here?
这里？
We've been waiting for you, Mr. Akimoto.
秋本先生 我们一直在等你
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
What are you doing here?
你们在这里做什么？
I was waiting for you.
我在等你
There's something we'd like to discuss.
有件事想跟你聊一聊
Discuss? There's nothing for me to discuss with you.
聊？我和你们没什么好聊的
You seem to be knowledgeable with stocks.
你似乎很懂股票
Mr. Akimoto, aren't you
秋本先生 你是不是
operating your stocks with money
用你从客户那里侵占的钱
you embezzled from your customers?
操作股票呢？
Give me a break. That's not true.
够了没？怎么可能！
Whatever money I use for my stocks, is none of your business.
再说我用什么钱买股票 都与你们无关
With all due respect…
恕我直言
-It is our business. -What?
-与我们有关 -什么？
We're here to talk with you as an agent
我们是代表关口静枝女士
for Ms. Shizue Sekiguchi.
来这里与你谈话
What do you mean?
你是什么意思？
Mr. Akimoto,
秋本先生
you never made Ms. Shizue's fixed deposit account
首先 你根本没有替静枝女士
of 20 million yen, in the first place.
开两千万日元的定期帐户
You took advantage of the fact that Keihin Bank was about to collapse
你利用京滨银行即将倒闭的机会
and decided to embezzle money.
决定侵吞金钱
That's why you cancelled
那就是为什么你取消静枝女士
Ms. Shizue's fixed account of 20 million yen with Tokyo Daiichi Bank
在东京第一银行的两千万日元定期
and took that money by promising to
拿走那笔钱
change her account to Keihin Bank.
将她的帐户转至京滨银行
The amount is accounted for.
金额正确
-Here is your confirmation. -Yes.
-这是你的确认单 -好
Thank you so much, Ms. Shizue.
静枝女士 非常谢谢你
No problem. I'm glad I was able to help you.
没事 很高兴我能帮上你
-Let me get you some tea. -Okay.
-我去帮你倒茶 -好的
-I'll bring the passbook tomorrow.
-明天我会拿存折过来 -好
But that money never went to Keihin Bank.
但是那些钱根本没进京滨银行
Because you deposited that money
因为你把那些钱
into your account at Tokyo First Stock.
存进你在东京第一证券的帐户
On May 14th,
5月14日那天
you made a deposit at the ATM in Kugahara.
在久原的一个提款机
You made ten deposits of two million yen each.
你存入十笔两百万日元
That's just false accusation.
那些都是不实指控
Do you have any proof to back this up?
你有任何证据佐证你的话吗？
I borrowed this from Ms. Shizue.
这是我向静枝女士借来的
The number printed on the passbook of the fixed account,
印在定期簿上的数字
and the one printed on the passbook of the checking account
还有印在活存簿上的数字
both look identical at first glance,
两者乍看相同
but the font is slightly different.
但是字型略有不同
You most likely took an unused passbook from the bank
你很可能是拿了银行里没用过的存折
and printed 20 million yen on your own.
自己印了两千万日元上去
PRINT
（打印）
KEIHIN FIXED DEPOSIT ACCOUNT
（京滨特别定期帐户）
This is counterfeit.
这个是伪造的
When Keihin Bank collapses,
当京滨银行倒闭时
it cannot guarantee any amount over ten million yen.
超过一千万日元的金额 都无法获得保证
That's why you kept Ms. Shizue's
那就是为什么你留下静枝女士的
20 million yen instead of depositing it into the bank.
两千万日元不存进银行
And after the bank collapsed,
在银行倒闭后
you were going to return
你归还一千万日元
ten million yen by making it seem like that was
让它看起来像是归还的金额
the recovered amount, and you were going to pocket the rest.
剩下的你则要中饱私囊
Am I wrong?
我说的没错吧？
You committed a crime using your position as a banker.
你利用你身为银行从业者的职位犯罪
Mr. Akimoto,
秋本先生
you cheated money out of the weak.
你骗走弱势者的钱
That's wrong.
那是不对的
You're disqualified as a banker.
你不配当银行从业者
How annoying.
真烦人
I don't care about that.
我才不在乎
I'm not a banker anymore.
我再也不是银行从业者了
She wasn't planning on using that money.
再说 她没打算使用那些钱
Why would she need that money when she doesn't
她也没几年好活了
have much longer to live?
要那些钱做什么呢？
I took good care of her.
我把她照顾得好好的
It's her fault that she got deceived.
她被骗是她的错
That money that her husband left her,
她先生留给她的那些钱
was a source of comfort for Ms. Shizue.
能让静枝女士感到安慰
That money was important to her because it protected her
那些钱对静枝女士很重要
like a good luck charm!
因为它就像幸运符那样保护她
Good luck charm? How foolish.
幸运符？多愚蠢啊
Money is money. It's all the same.
钱就是钱 钱都是一样的
No, it's not.
不一样
The money Ms. Shizue protected,
静枝女士保护的钱
and the dirty money you handle are not the same!
和你掌握的不义之财是不一样的
-Shut up! -No, I won't!
-吵死了 闭嘴！ -我不要！
Ms. Shizue entrusted her precious money to you because she liked you.
静枝女士因为喜欢你 才将她宝贵的钱托付给你
But you took advantage of her.
你却利用她
She said that you were like a real grandson to her.
她说你就像她真正的孙子
She was happy she got to help you.
她很高兴她能帮上你
She said people are more important than the money she lost.
她说人比她损失的钱重要
Ms. Shizue
静枝女士
still believes in you.
依然相信你
Even if she finds out the truth, she'll most likely be more worried about you
就算她发现真相 她很可能担心你
than about her money.
胜过她的钱
That's who she is.
她就是那样的人
But
可是
even if Ms. Shizue forgives you,
就算静枝女士原谅你
I will never forgive you!
我也绝对不会原谅你
We've been waiting.
等候多时了
I'm Ito from Kugahara Police.
我是久原警局的伊藤
Are you Teruo Akimoto?
你是秋本辉夫吗？
We'd like to question you at the station, so please come with us.
我们想在警局询问详情 请跟我们走
-Damn it! -Hey, you!
-可恶！ -喂！
-Let go of me! -Stop!
-放开我！ -别动！
-Hanasaki! -Calm down!
-花琦！ -冷静！
Let go of me!
喂 放开我！
What should I tell her?
该怎么跟她说呢？
Ms. Shizue.
静枝女士
Um…
那个…
It's about Mr. Akimoto…
秋本先生的事…
Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you, Ms. Hanasaki.
谢谢你 花琦小姐
Not at all.
没什么
EMPLOYEES OF TOKYO DAIICHI BANK HELP WITH ARREST
（东京第一银行员工协助逮捕 京滨银行从业者诈欺嫌疑犯）
What a horrible crime.
这起事件也太过分了
Will they get back the money that he conned out of them?
他骗走的钱 他们能拿回来吗？
Tokyo First Stock is working with the police,
东京第一证券正在和警方合作
and I hear they'll get most of it back.
听说大部分的钱都能拿回来
I'm glad, otherwise it'll be too unfair.
这样就好 不然就太不公平了
Yeah.
就是啊
But you two are really amazing.
不过你们两个太厉害了
"Employees at Tokyo Daiichi Bank helped with the arrest."
“东京第一银行员工协助逮捕”
Oh, well, not really…
没有啦
You might get
你们可能会
a certificate of appreciation from the police.
拿到警方的感谢证书
You think so?
真的吗？
Yeah, they might print your picture too.
是啊 说不定还会印你们的照片
No way! Really?
不可能 真的吗？
I should go to the hair salon, and the spa beforehand.
我应该先去做头发和水疗
Oh no, what should I do if people start noticing me.
糟糕 要是大家开始注意我怎么办？
I'm sure it's just a coincidence, but Branch Inspection
我相信只是碰巧 不过稽核班的
seems to have had a big part in solving this case.
似乎在解决这个案子中起了很大作用
Normally, they're not allowed to stick their heads in other banks' businesses.
正常情况下是不容许他们 插手别家银行的业务
Yes.
是
But in the end,
但是到最后
it improved the image of Tokyo Daiichi Bank,
这件事提升了东京第一银行的形象
so it's an achievement--
所以这是一个成就
-Achievement? -Oh, no…
-成就？ -不是
No. They did something unnecessary once again.
不 他们再次做了不必要的事
Sir, it's time for your meeting with Chairman Itami.
本部长 您和伊丹会长 碰面的时间到了
Okay.
好的
The Itami Group
伊丹集团
is about to begin the Ginza Redevelopment Project.
即将启动银座再开发计划
Getting the contract as the coordinating bank,
取得协力银行的合约
is our biggest chance
是最好的机会
to make our bank known to the world.
让我们银行举世闻名
Yes, sir.
是
-Hurry up, Mr. Soma. -Yeah.
-相马先生 快一点 -好
Ms. Shizue is waiting for us.
静枝女士在等我们
I know.
我知道
But I wonder why she wanted to see us all of a sudden.
但是怎么回事？ 她怎么突然要见我们？
She wants to thank us both.
她想谢谢我们两个
Thank us, huh… Oh,
谢谢我们…
maybe she'll set you up with someone again.
也许她又要安排你和某个人相亲
I don't think so.
不会吧？
All right! Let's go. Good evening.
好 我们走 晚上好
I'm home.
我回来了
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
抱歉 让你久等了
Ms. Hanasaki, your dad is so much fun.
花琦小姐 你爸爸好风趣
You are too, with so many interesting stories.
你也是 有那么多有趣的故事
Oh, stop it…
没有啦
They've really hit it off.
他们真是一拍即合
-It seems like it. -Sit down.
-似乎是这样 -坐吧
-Yes. -Thank you.
-好 -谢谢
-Here you go.
-给你
Thank you so much for all of your help.
非常谢谢你们的帮忙
I'm glad to see you doing well.
看到你很有精神 我们就放心了
-You're doing better than before. -You think so? Thank you.
-你的气色比以前更好了 -是吗？谢谢你
And as a way to thank you…
为了感谢你们
-Here it comes! -Um…
来了
You don't need to set me up with anyone.
你不必安排我去相亲
You're meeting someone?
相亲？
It's a great chance, Hanasaki.
这是大好机会 花琦
I found a great person. It's a perfect match…
我找到一个很棒的人 非常适合
for Mr. Soma.
相马先生
-What? -For Mr. Soma?
-什么？ -给相马先生的？
This person is also a divorcee. What do you say?
这个人也离过婚 你觉得怎么样？
Oh… no, I'm not really interested in that…
不用 我对那个不是很有兴趣
Oh come on, it's a great chance.
别这样 这是大好机会
-Try it this once. -I think so too.
-这次试试看 -我也这么想
Stop that… wait a minute.
别说了 等等
-How about you? -What?
-给你如何？ -什么呀？
-That's a great idea. -No way!
-好主意 -不可能
I'm too old for that. Mr. Soma, you try it.
我太老了 不合适 相马先生 你去
-No, you should try it. -No, I have Mai to think about.
-不 你应该去 -不 我有舞要操心
-Come on, Mr. Soma. -No, it's yours.
-拜托 相马先生 -不 这是给你的
Come on, Mr. Soma. I'm begging you!
拜托 相马先生 我求你
That's the notorious Itami.
那就是恶名昭彰的伊丹少东？
Nice to meet you, Hanasaki.
请多关照啰 花琦小姐
He's so arrogant.
也太傲慢了
Your loan was denied?
你的贷款被拒绝了？
I have to protect this company.
我必须保护这家公司
-Where's Itami? -It's going to fail.
-伊丹在哪里？ -会失败的
They'll go bankrupt sooner or later.
他们迟早会破产
You're the damn fool.
你才是可恶的笨蛋